Ryan Evans

Cleveland, Ohio, United States



rdevans87@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ryanevanscreative



3306711076



https://www.ryanevanscodes.com

Summary

Product Owner with leadership experience and strong technical background supporting a variety of cross-platform software applications. Professional certifications in Full Stack Web Development, Project Management, Agile Methodologies, Software QA Testing, and Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals. I'm a creative thinker and problem solver with a passion for technology and entertainment.

Experience

mri Product Owner

MRI Software

Jul 2021 - Present (7 months +)

Responsible for developing user stories and packaging the features into product releases.

- Manage card break down, provide test case scenario input, and documentation approval.
- Assisting the Product Manager with developing the product roadmap and vision.
- Prioritizing enhancement requests and technical issues with product development team.
- Ensuring execution and delivery of solutions valued by the markets we serve.
- Effectively manage multiple strategic initiatives, work assignments and projects.

Customer Service Specialist

IMDb.com

Jul 2019 - Jun 2021 (2 years)

Acted quickly to diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues for IMDb's website and mobile apps under tight deadlines to meet 24-hour SLA.

- Collaborated with development team to file bug reports, resolve incoming tickets, and manage customer accounts.
- Contributed to self-help knowledge base and implemented new support procedures that reduced incoming contacts and ticket resolution times.
- Demonstrated ability to solve challenging technical issues and make data-driven decisions to improve customer satisfaction.
- Built fast and effective working relationships with team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.

Sr. Product Technical Support Analyst

Cast & Crew

Apr 2017 - Jul 2019 (2 years 4 months)

Managed product implementation efforts for all early adopters of Studio+ (SaaS) software as a file management and collaboration tool for each phase of film and television production.

 Acted as liaison between product manager and engineering team to communicate relevant software updates, product enhancements, and implementation requests to support team.

- · Provided on-site/remote training demonstrations for end-users and established department best practices and policies for support team to follow and communicate to end-users.
- Assisted with QA testing, bug reporting, submitting end-user feedback, enhancement requests, and tracked software updates/releases using Agile project management with Scrum in Jira.
- Managed relationships through effective communication and collaboration between multiple internal and external stakeholders

Sales Support Associate, Final Draft Inc.

Cast & Crew

Apr 2015 - Apr 2017 (2 years 1 month)

Responded to a high volume of incoming customer inquiries via phone, email, and live chat to drive sales and provide an excellent customer experience.

- Assisted with QA testing and software launch of two product releases: Final Draft 10 (2016) & Final Draft 11 (2018).
- · Used Salesforce (CRM) to manage interactions with existing customers and identify new opportunities to increase sales.
- Performed in depth product demonstrations and sales presentations for industry professionals at screenwriting conferences and promotional events.
- · Position required a strong attention to detail, exceptional service skills, and the ability to communicate effectively.

Education

The Ohio State University

Professional Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Web Development

2021 - 2021

The Ohio State University Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

College of Engineering and Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE). Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+,

Other Skills & Experience:

-Bootstrap, iQuery, Node.is, Express.is, React.is, MySQL, MongoDB, Git,

Progressive & Responsive Web Applications, APIs, JSON, AJAX, DOM, OOP, ORM, MVC, ODM

-Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Software QA Testing, Agile Project Management, Scrum, Kandan, Mobile First Approach, UX/UI Design, Pseudocode

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Communication and Media Studies

2007 - 2011

Studied the global reach of communication and media among the world's cultures. Explored ethical issues of journalism, advertising, law, and public relations.

Other Skills & Experience:

- -Examined web design, information architecture, page layouts, and user research. Developed communication strategies that are responsive to cultural requirements of new media.
- -Vice-President of the National Broadcasting Society's UCF chapter. Acted as Liaison for student affairs, responsible for maintaining a professional relationship between students and faculty at UCFTV.

Licenses & Certifications

Software Testing Bootcamp - Udemy UC-4YR07X42

Project Management Professional (PMP) - PRINCE2.com SIDL-6550166366299791360

Agile Master Training - Alison 3366-19827817

Microsoft Certified Azure Al Fundamentals - Microsoft 1119-4694

Skills

Leadership • Software QA Testing • Web Development • HTML5 • Sales • Technical Support • Customer Service • Video Production • Troubleshooting • Web Design